<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipes>
    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Spicy Chicken Burger</recipeName>
        <step>
            Step 1: Make the Franks® Red Hot lime crema in a small bowl, whisk together the sour cream,
                    Frank’s® Red Hot Sauce, lime juice and zest, and salt.
            Step 2: Set aside. Crema can be made up to a week in advance, stored in an airtight container in the refrigerator
            Step 3: In a large bowl, combine the ground chicken, fresno chiles, Frank’s RedHot® Sauce, salt, garlic powder,
                    and onion powder and mix gently with your hands until just combined.
            Step 4: Divide the mixture into 4 even portions, then shape into 4-inch (10 cm) patties using wet
                    hands to make it easier to shape.
            Step 5: Heat a 12-inch (30 cm) cast iron skillet over medium heat.
            Step 6: When the skillet is hot, add the canola oil. When the oil starts to shimmer,
                    add the chicken patties and cook until the bottom is golden brown and the bottom
                    ⅓ of the patty looks cooked with a white hue, about 5 minutes. Flip the patties and
                    add a slice of pepper Jack cheese. Reduce heat to low and continue to cook until the
                    internal temperature of the center of the patties reaches 165°F (75°C), about 5 more minutes.
            Step 7: Assemble the burgers: Spread Frank’s® Red Hot lime crema on both sides of each bun. Place a
                    lettuce on each bottom bun, then top with the patties, avocado, and pickled fresnos. Top with
                    the top bun and serve immediately.
            Step 8: Enjoy!
        </step>
        <privacy>0</privacy>
    </recipe>
    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Tuna SandWich</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. In a medium bowl, combine the tuna, mayonnaise, celery, onion, bell pepper, capers and lemon juice.
            2. Mix with a fork until thoroughly combined. Season to taste with salt and pepper.
            3. Serve on the sandwich bread of your choice.
        </step>
        <privacy>0</privacy>
    </recipe>
    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Kimchi Fried Rice</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. In a large saucepan of 3 cups water, cook rice according to package instructions; set aside.
            2. In a small bowl, whisk together kimchi juice, soy sauce, gochujang and sesame oil.
            3. Heat canola oil in a large skillet over medium high heat. Add garlic, onion and ginger, and cook,
               stirring frequently, until onions have become translucent, about 2-3 minutes.
            4. Stir in kimchi, mushrooms and carrots. Cook, stirring constantly, until mushrooms are tender, about 3-4 minutes.
            5. Stir in rice, kale and kimchi juice mixture until the kale has wilted, about 2-3 minutes.
            6. Serve immediately with eggs, nori strips, green onions and sesame seeds, if desired.
        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>

    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Scramble Eggs</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. BEAT eggs, milk, salt and pepper in a medium bowl until blended.
            2. HEAT butter in a large nonstick skillet over medium heat until hot.
            3. POUR in egg mixture. As eggs begin to set, gently
            4. PULL the eggs across the pan with a spatula, forming large soft curds.
            5. CONTINUE cooking—pulling, lifting and folding eggs—until thickened and no visible
               liquid egg remains. Do not stir constantly.
            6. REMOVE from heat.
            7. SERVE immediately.
        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>

    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Chicken Tikka Masala</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. In a large saucepan of 2 cups water, cook rice according to package instructions; set aside.
            2. Heat canola oil in a large stockpot or Dutch oven over medium heat. Season chicken with salt and pepper,
               to taste. Add chicken and onion to the stockpot and cook until golden, about 4-5 minutes.
            3. Stir in tomato paste, garlic, ginger, garam masala, chili powder and turmeric until fragrant, about 1 minute.
            4. Stir in tomato sauce and chicken stock; season with salt and pepper, to taste. Bring to a boil;
               reduce heat and simmer, stirring occasionally, until reduced and slightly thickened, about 10 minutes.
            5. Stir in heavy cream until heated through, about 1 minute.
            6. Serve immediately with rice, garnished with cilantro, if desired.
        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>

    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Garlic Chilli Fried Rice</recipeName>
        <step>
            Step by step recipe for Chilli Garlic sauce:
            1. Boil dried red chilies in water for 2 minutes. Drain and let it cool.
            2. Grind the chilies coarsely along with garlic, vinegar, salt and sugar.
            3. Heat a pan and pour oil (preferably sesame oil).
            4. Pour the chili garlic paste to this and sauté for a minute till it starts boiling.
            5. Mix the corn flour in half cup water and combine with the paste and let it simmer and thicken.

            Step by step recipe for Chili Garlic Fried rice:
            1. Wash, soak and cook the rice, with double measure of water, pepper powder, star anise and crushed garlic. (Check how to make vegetable fried rice, for exact cooking instructions for perfect fried rice). Transfer the cooked rice to a tray, spread well and allow to cool well.
            2. Chop the garlic and vegetables finely.
            3. Cut red chilies into fine rounds or crush red chillies and keep aside.
            4. Heat oil in a thick wok/ pan and add finely chopped garlic. If you like burnt garlic, let it brown slightly (or fry for half a minute) then add red chilies cut into rounds.
            5. Next, add chopped beans and fry for a minute, then add chopped carrot and continue to stir fry for another minute, followed by cabbage, onion and capsicum, enough salt and stir fry on high flame for a minute.
            6. Add the spring onion whites and stir fry for few seconds.
            7. Add the chilli garlic sauce, soy sauce, vinegar and Tomato sauce.
            8. Combine well and mix in the cooked rice in batches to ensure proper mixing and add the celery and Spring onion greens. Adjust the salt.
        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>

    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Chicken Dum Biryani</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. Wash rice few times till the water runs clear. Soak in ample amount of water for 30 mins. Drain and set aside.
            2. Bring 2 to 2 ½ liters water to a boil in a pot or a cooker. Add bay leaf and shahi jeera. You can also use cinnamon,
               cloves and cardamoms. If you do not like to get a bite of the spices in the rice, you can also tie these in a muslin
               cloth and add to the pot.
            3. Meanwhile, Heat 3 tbsp. oil in a biryani pot , handi or pan. Add sliced onions and fry evenly until golden.
            4. These onions lend a unique and authentic flavor, so do not skip these.
            5. When they turn dark brown, set aside  ¼ portion of these fried onions.
            6. When the water comes to a boil, add salt and drained rice and cook until al dente or 90 % done.
            Making gravy for chicken dum biryani recipe
            7. While the rice cooks, let us make the chicken ready. To the rest of the onions, add 1 small bay leaf,
               star anise, ½ tsp shahi jeera, 3 cardamoms, 4 cloves. Saute just for a min without burning.
            8. Add 1 tbsp. ginger garlic paste.
            9. Saute on a medium flame until the raw smell of ginger garlic goes off.
            10. Add chicken.
            11. Saute for 2 to 3 mins until the chicken turns white in color. Sprinkle salt.
            12. Add biryani masala, red chili powder, turmeric and green chilies. I use this HOMEMADE BIRYANI MASALA.
                Just a reminder about the rice, do check it.
            13. Mix everything well and fry for 3 mins. After that cover and cook on a low flame for 3 to 4 mins for
                the chicken to release the moisture.
            14. Add 1 cup thick curd / yogurt.
            15. Stir, cover and cook on a medium flame until chicken is soft and tender.
            16. While the chicken cooks, check the rice. Drain off the rice to a colander when cooked to al dente. The rice
                must be 90 % cooked meaning you must feel the bite when you bite through a rice grain. Rice should be firm and
                grainy but not mushy.
            17. When the chicken is cooked completely, a thick gravy is left in the pot with oil separated. Check the salt now and add more if needed. Stir well and sprinkle chopped coriander and pudina leaves.
                Layering chicken dum biryani
            18. Layer the rice over the chicken gravy. Sprinkle fried onions, pudina and coriander leaves.
                You can also add the optional ingredients – pour the saffron soaked milk, ghee and kewra water evenly.
                For multilayer check the recipe card below.
            19. Cover the pot with a foil or a thick clean moist cloth.
            20. Cover with a air tight lid to trap the steam or dum. If you do not have a
                tight lid then you can place a heavy pot over the lid. You can mix 1 ½ cups atta
                with water and make a dough. Stick the dough to the rim of the lid. Press it off on
                to the pot, for a air tight seal. Place this pot on a hot tawa and cook for about 12 to 15 mins
                on a medium heat. Once done switch off and allow to rest for at least 20 mins.
            21. Aromatic hyderanbadi chicken dum biriyani is ready.
            22. Serve hot or warm with raita and shorva.
        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>

    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Chicken Taco</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. In a small bowl, combine chili powder, cumin, paprika, oregano,
               garlic powder, 1 teaspoon salt and 1/2 teaspoon pepper.
               Season chicken with chili powder mixture.

            2. Heat canola oil in a large skillet over medium high heat.
               Working in batches, add chicken to the skillet in a single layer and cook until golden brown and cooked through,
               reaching an internal temperature of 165 degrees F, about 4-5 minutes per side.
               Let cool before dicing into bite-size pieces.

            3. Serve chicken in tortillas, topped with pico de gallo, avocado, cilantro and lime.

        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>

    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Breakfast Burrito</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. Cook the potatoes in bacon fat.
            All good breakfast burritos have some sort of potato component. To keep prep to an absolute minimum,
            we use frozen hash browns. They cook quickly and crisp up nicely.
            2. Season the eggs at the last minute.
            According to Gordon Ramsay, adding salt in the beginning draws out moisture and makes eggs watery.
            So wait to do it until the very end.
            3. Use a sharp, tangy, or spicy cheese.
            Obviously cheddar is perfect because it melts nicely. But gouda (sharp), goat cheese (tangy), or
            pepper jack spicy work really too. Mild varieties like mozzarella or Monterey jack are totally
            acceptable but they do not add nearly as much flavor.
            4. Do not use a cold tortilla.
            It will be really hard to fold and roll and will likely break on you. Warm or room temp makes things
            much easier. And if you are still struggling knowing how to do it, watch around :30 of this Cheesy
            Baked Burrito vid.
        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>
    <recipe>
        <recipeName>Chicken Wings</recipeName>
        <step>
            1. Preheat oven to 425°F. Dab wings with paper towels until completely dry.
            2. Toss wings with flour, salt and pepper. Remove any excess flour and brush with olive oil (or use an olive oil spray).
            3. Line a pan with foil and then place parchment paper on top (you may need 2 pans) and bake 35 minutes turning at 20 minutes.
            4. Meanwhile, combine sauce ingredients in a small pan. Bring to a boil, reduce heat and simmer about 10 minutes or until slightly
                thickened and sauce coats the back of a spoon.
            5. Take wings from oven, toss with sauce and return to the oven for 10 minutes, turning after 5 minutes.
            6. Allow to cool 10 minutes. As the sauce cools, it thickens. Stir the wings every few minutes to coat in the sauce as it thickens.
        </step>
    <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>


</recipes>