<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<recipes>
    <recipe>
        <recipeID>10000</recipeID>
        <recipeName>Spicy Chicken Burger</recipeName>
        <step>
            Step 1: Make the Frank’s® Red Hot lime crema in a small bowl, whisk together the sour cream, Frank’s® Red Hot Sauce, lime juice and zest, and salt.
            Step 2: Set aside. Crema can be made up to a week in advance, stored in an airtight container in the refrigerator
            Step 3: In a large bowl, combine the ground chicken, fresno chiles, Frank’s RedHot® Sauce, salt, garlic powder, and onion powder and mix gently with your hands until just combined.
            Step 4: Divide the mixture into 4 even portions, then shape into 4-inch (10 cm) patties using wet hands to make it easier to shape.
            Step 5: Heat a 12-inch (30 cm) cast iron skillet over medium heat.
            Step 6: When the skillet is hot, add the canola oil. When the oil starts to shimmer, add the chicken patties and cook until the bottom is golden brown and the bottom ⅓ of the patty looks cooked with a white hue, about 5 minutes. Flip the patties and add a slice of pepper Jack cheese. Reduce heat to low and continue to cook until the internal temperature of the center of the patties reaches 165°F (75°C), about 5 more minutes .
            Step 7: Assemble the burgers: Spread Frank’s® Red Hot lime crema on both sides of each bun. Place a lettuce on each bottom bun, then top with the patties, avocado, and pickled fresnos. Top with the top bun and serve immediately.
            Step 8: Enjoy!
        </step>
        <privacy>0</privacy>
    </recipe>
    <recipe>
        <recipeID>10001</recipeID>
        <recipeName>Tuna SandWich</recipeName>
        <step>
            In a medium bowl, combine the tuna, mayonnaise, celery, onion, bell pepper, capers and lemon juice.
            Mix with a fork until thoroughly combined. Season to taste with salt and pepper.
            Serve on the sandwich bread of your choice.
        </step>
        <privacy>0</privacy>
    </recipe>
    <recipe>
        <recipeID>10002</recipeID>
        <recipeName>Kimchi Fried Rice</recipeName>
        <step>
            In a large saucepan of 3 cups water, cook rice according to package instructions; set aside.
            In a small bowl, whisk together kimchi juice, soy sauce, gochujang and sesame oil.
            Heat canola oil in a large skillet over medium high heat. Add garlic, onion and ginger, and cook, stirring frequently, until onions have become translucent, about 2-3 minutes.
            Stir in kimchi, mushrooms and carrots. Cook, stirring constantly, until mushrooms are tender, about 3-4 minutes.
            Stir in rice, kale and kimchi juice mixture until the kale has wilted, about 2-3 minutes.
            Serve immediately with eggs, nori strips, green onions and sesame seeds, if desired.
        </step>
        <privacy>1</privacy>
    </recipe>
</recipes>